

Axel Alavedra

Programmer

About

Phone:

+34 667 75 75 18

Email:

axel.alavedra@gmail.com

Portfolio:

axelalavedra.com

Linkedin:

Axel Alavedra Cabello

Address:

Terrassa, Barcelona, Spain

Languages

English: High
Spanish: Native
Catalan: Native

Profile

Programmer with over four years of experience in the video game industry and shipped PC/Console titles.

My areas of expertise are Gameplay and AI, with excellent software design and debugging skills.

Great passion for making games and working together with design teams.

Career Summary

Sep 2023 - Present

Al Programmer at Melbot

- Unreal Engine, GAS
- Al Behaviors
- Al Combat Systems
- Al Decision Making & Tools
- Gameplay mechanics

Sep 2021 - Sep 2023

Gameplay Programmer at

Melbot

- Unity
- Development Tools
- Gameplay mechanics
- Al Behaviors
- Al Systems & Tools:
 - Behavior Tree Tool
 - Position Query System Tool
 - o Combat Circle System
 - Perception System

July 2021 - Sep 2021 Intern Programmer at Melbot

- Unity
- Gameplay mechanics
- Al Behaviors
- Sole developer for PS4 port

October 2016 - May 2017 Intern Programmer at ViOD

Games Studio

- Player actions
- Al Behaviors
- Gameplay mechanics
- Scoring system

Professional Skills

Programming:

C++, C#

AI:

State Machine, Behavior Tree, Utility Al, Decision Making, Pathfinding

Game Engines:

Unity, Unreal Engine

Development:

Debugging, Profiling, Architecture Design

Shipped Titles

- Nick Jr. Party Adventure -
 - October 2024
 - PC & Consoles
 - Unity
- My Little Pony: A Maretime Bay Adventure - May 2022
 - PC & Consoles
 - Unity

Educational Training

CITM (UPC)

Bachelor's degree in Design and Development of Videogames

 Attended from Sept. 2017 to June 2021

Escola PIA Balmes

Certificate of Higher Education, Computer Games and Programming Skills

- Attended from Sept. 2015 to June 2017
- Unity Certified Programmer